we need to write a program that's going
to
print out groups of words from this
words array
that are anagrams so they have the same
letters but the letters are in a
different order
and we see a little code example in our
words array you can see that demo dome
and mode for example these are anagrams
of each other
so the first thing we need to do is just
to break down this problem
a little bit and consider how we're
going to approach it
so we've been given an array and the
first step here is simply going to be to
iterate over the array
we're going to organize these anagrams
into a hash
the key of the hash is going to be the
word alphabetically sorted
so on line one of the example code we
were given
demo would be the key and the value
associated with that key
is going to be an array of all of the
anagrams of that word
so if demo were our key
then the value associated with that key
would be an array
of the strings demo dome and mode
so in order to get our key we want to
sort each word into alphabetical order
as we iterate through this array
if this key already exists
we want to append the current word
into the value which is going to be an
array
otherwise we want to create a new key
with this sorted word
so now that we've kind of considered our
approach let's transform this into code
the first step here is simply to
initialize a result hash
and we'll populate this hash with our
key value pairs as we iterate through
the words array
we can iterate through words using each
each word is going to be passed as an
argument to the block
now the next step of our approach is to
sort each word into alphabetical order
let's hop over into irb to see how we
can do this
let's say we have the string mode we can
sort this string into alphabetical order
by splitting it into an array of
characters
calling sort to sort those characters
and then joining this array of
characters now
sorted characters back into a string
and when i hit enter you can see that
the sorted string
is demo
if i use that same code on the string
dome again we see the string demo is the
sorted result
so as we iterate through this array we
will sort the characters alphabetically
to create the keys of this result hash
and let's store that in a variable key
if our result hash already has this key
we can use the hash method has key here
which returns a boolean and we'll pass
in the
key that we assigned on line 12 as the
argument
then we want to push the current word
into the array that will be the value
associated with this key
looking up at our notes on line 7 we can
see that otherwise we simply want to
create a new key in the hash
with this sorted word
now when we create this new key we're
going to
assign its value to be an array
we'll place the current word in that
array
and this is why on line 14 we can invoke
the push method
on the value associated with an existing
key
at this point let's just output the
result hash
so we see our result hash we've got five
key value pairs
and each value is an array or a list
of the anagrams so this looks pretty
good
but looking at the example output and
the problem description
we want to output only the values here
i'm going to remove the notes that we
previously used
to make room for a little bit more code
here
we've got our list of anagrams stored in
the result hash
and we want to output only the values
only this list of anagrams
we don't need to output the key
so we can invoke the each value method
on our result hash
each value will be passed to the block
and then let's use p to output each of
these lists
we'll run our code again and we expect
our output to look like the example that
we were given
and that's what we see